<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Chaopolis</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Chaopolis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 16:07:19 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NEATL Theory 1: Introducing Neuroeconomics</title>
      <link>/post/neatl1-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 16:07:19 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/neatl1-theory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I. Motivations for and Goals of NEATL Theory, and an Important Caveat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Neuroeconomic Approach to Language, what I&amp;rsquo;ll call NEATL Theory, is a theory or set of ideas about the neurophysiology of structured
(or &amp;ldquo;meaningful&amp;rdquo;) volitional action, focusing particularly on the mechanics of motivation and value, to describe and explain language use.
It combines a number of ideas. Most simply, it is an attempt to model and explain
the mechanics of language through the structures, concepts, and approaches of neuroeconomics, a field developed by Paul Glimcher and others.
Neuroeconomics is &amp;ndash; to start with a grossly oversimplifying gist &amp;ndash; a framework using the structure and mechanics of
&amp;ldquo;decision-making&amp;rdquo; cortical maps, as they represent the utility of plans and trigger them into action, and their support mechanisms
(most importantly meta-action maps) to manifest (and thereby explain) voluntary action
of humans and animals and the (internal) structures and conditions under which it operates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/principles/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ndash; title: &amp;ldquo;Proposed Principles of Human Being&amp;rdquo; date: 2017-08-25T15:25:01+09:00
draft: true I reserving this space to list some general principles and important points of my theory of human being, at various degrees of priority and inflexibility, which I hope to amend over time as needed.
 At the root of the free will problem is the personal identity problem. Mechanisms integrating situations, norms, motivations, and volition are mediating the will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/sacredcows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sacredcows/</guid>
      <description>First, it&amp;rsquo;s useful to clear the road of the detris of past frameworks and take the attitude that nothing is sacred. At the center of any theory should, above all, be established empirical findings. After that we have principles of theory-building that include self-consistency and base principles that we can observe appearing over and over with some confidence. The first means it&amp;rsquo;s one coherent system where all the parts work together according to a consistent framework, not fragmented systems for each type of function with no idea how they interrelate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>